

P Electronic City, Bangalore

+91 797-860-9324

☑ ankit.nyk2331@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/ankit-nayak21

# **Summary**

### 5year+ year of experience in Software Development

In the course of my career, I have worked as a Developer, Tech Lead, Project Manager, and Client Success Manager for multiple projects. I have worked with ZS as a consultant, Handled pharma clients i.e Amgen and Pfizer, and worked on the arch design and implementation for pharma application PKM.

I'm a professional & experienced in working in a fast-paced environment with strong organizational, technical, and interpersonal skills. Detail-oriented and resourceful in completing projects and also able to handle multi-task effectively.

As a lead, I always make sure of deliveries along with taking care of my peer's interests, learning, and development. and myself I always look for challenging work and trying to resolve the problems in an efficient way

# Work experience

# **Technology Lead**

Sept 2019 - Present

Knowledge Lens

### Product and Knowledge Management Application (PKM)

- Data Ingestion Module for Pfizer to Fluxa PKM Application
  - Design and delivered iRME solution to Pfizer, by collaborating with Infosys, Rockwell, and Pfizer
  - o Introduced Visual Recipe Builder(VRB) with Branching and Looping functionality for Pharma purpose.

#### • Performance Enhancement

- Resolve MongoDB data size limit of 16MB in a single document by splitting the document.
- Optimize the search queries in MongoDB and Python script for better performance.

## · Project Lead

 Lead a team of 10 developers 2 Quality Analysts and 2 Clients for the project. The engagement involved information gathering, project development, managing maintenance, and delivery of the project

#### Non-Conformance Trending(NLP)

#### · Clustering Module

- Build NLP module to perform clustering based on the mentioned description
- Used stop words, abbreviations, key identifiers for the algorithm

#### • AWS Lambda, Step Function, and Redshift Module

- Lambda module to get trigger, fetch the data from S3 and forward it for processing
- Step function to fetch orchestrator running status,
- Databricks for processing and transforming massive quantities of data and exploring the data
- Ingest the processed parquet file data to Redshift and create reports in Spotfire
- The application was used by Drug Quality Controller and SME to see any deviation from the marked quality parameters
- Technologies used Python, SparkSql, S3, Lambda, Databricks, Redshift, Spotfire

#### Process Development and HLEE (Holistic Lab Execution Environment)

- Enterprise Data Lake with Real-time ingestion for experiments
- Build Arch for the project and module for master orchestrating the pipelines.
- Build Ingestion module to handle Full and Incremental loads.
- Build module to integrate the EC2 machines with Databricks.
- Build Redshift Module to ingest the parquet file from s3 to Redshift for better performance.
- Build Spotfire report for easy monitoring of the ingestion, Alert, and maintenance

## Junior Data Scientist

Nov 2017 - Sept 2019

Knowledge Lens

#### **GLENS (Environment Monitoring System)**

- Preprocessing and cleaning of the data received from the Devices and Analyzers across different states of India
- Analysis based on recentness & frequency to calculate the AQIs exceedance.
- Used Python and R shiny for Interactive reports and Automation.
- Used Elasticsearch and Mysql as the secondary database for the use case.
- Re-designed and implemented a module/service to provide the capability of creating AQIs Dashboard

# **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages Python, Java, R shiny Framework/Web-Services Tornado, Flask

Databases MySql, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Redshift, PostgreSQL

Operating System Linux, Windows
Data Visualization Tool Spotfire, R Shiny

Development Tool Pycharm, Vi/Vim, Visual Studio Code

Project Build Tool Pycharm, Databricks, Gitlab

CMS/DMS Jira, Git, Service Now, Azure DevOps

Others Data-structure & Algorithms, AWS Lambda, Spark SQL

# **Education**

#### **Master of Business Administration**

2014 - 2016

Utkal University, Bhubaneswar

Finance and Marketing: Management Consulting Association, Strategic Operations Mangement

## **Bachelor of Business Administration**

2011 - 2014

B.J.B Autonomous College, Bhubaneswar

# **Awards & Recognition**

- November 2018: Awarded with 'Best Initiator of the Year' at Knowledge Lens. Awarded for delivering extra miles across all departments
- August 2020: Appreciation from Captain Manivannan on behalf of the **Government of Karnataka for voluntary work for the COVID-19** pandemic by involving in various IT initiatives driven by Knowledge Lens.
- March 2021: Awarded with 'Star of the Month Award' for proactive communication, zero laxity, and on-time project delivery.
  - Link: https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6787331795546468352/
- Sepetember2021: Awarded with 'Extra Mile Award' for impeccable performance and Excellence at work every day.

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6881097984071884800/

Created with **TVisualCV**